Husband. Father. Fighter. Hero. Once you choose hope, anything is possible.
Super/Man: The Christopher Reeve Story is a
documentary film directed by Ian Bonhôte.
Christopher Reeve portrayed the Man of Steel in four Superman films and played dozens of other roles that displayed his talent and range as
an actor, before being injured in a near-fatal horse-riding accident in 1995 that left him paralyzed from the neck down.
After becoming a quadriplegic, he became a charismatic leader and activist in the quest to find a cure
for spinal cord injuries, as well as a passionate advocate for disability rights and care.
Self (archive footage), played by Christopher Reeve.
Self - Christopher's Son, played by Will Reeve.
Self - Christopher's Daughter, played by Alexandra Reeve Givens.
Self, played by Gae Exton.
Self, played by Glenn Close.
Self, played by Jeff Daniels.
Super/Man: The Christopher Reeve Story is a 2024 documentary film about the life of American actor Christopher Reeve after
a horse riding accident left him paralyzed, and his subsequent work as an activist for disability rights.
The documentary was directed by Ian Bonhôte and Peter Ettedgui, who co-wrote the script with Otto
Burnham; its title is a reference to Reeve's role as Superman in the 1978–1987 Superman films.
Reeve's children Alexandra Reeve Givens, Matthew Reeve,
and Will Reeve are featured in the film.
A British-American venture, the film is a co-production by Words + Pictures, Passion Pictures, and Misfits
Entertainment in association with Jenco Films, and was acquired for distribution by Warner Bros.
Pictures, DC Studios, HBO Documentary Films, CNN
Films, and the streaming service Max.
Super/Man: The Christopher Reeve Story premiered on January 19, 2024, at the Sundance Film Festival, and received a limited
theatrical release in collaboration with Fathom Events in the United States on September 21 and 25, 2024.
The film was wide released in North America on October 11.
It received universal acclaim from critics and audiences alike, and was named one of
the top five documentary films of 2024 by the National Board of Review.
Among other accolades, it won the Best Documentary award at the British Academy Film Awards and the Producers Guild of
America, and six awards at the Critics' Choice Documentary Awards (including Best Documentary Feature).
The film explores themes of biography, based on true
story, docudrama, disability, quadriplegic.